Guide to the Thornton Wilder Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1915-1991; Series II; 21.27; (56 boxes)
  - NOVELS
    - The Eighth Day
      - Setting typescript, corrected: "Second Master Copy", 1967 (Box 99, Folder 2417-2418)
      - Setting typescript, corrected: "Second Master Copy", 1967 (Box 100, Folder 2419-2421)
      - Setting typescript, corrected: "Fourth Master Copy", 1967 (Box 100, Folder 2422-2426)
      - Galley proof, corrected, n.d.
      - Page proof, incomplete: "First off the press", 1968 (Box 101, Folder 2427-2429)
      - Holograph manuscript: "Final text, queries", 1967 (Box 102, Folder 2430)
      - Photocopy pages with Wilder's final corrections, 1967 (Box 102, Folder 2431)
      - Page proof, complete, 1967 (Box 102, Folder 2432)
      - "Uncorrected proof," reviewer's copy, 1967 (Box 102, Folder 2433)
      - Photocopies of pages annotated by Wilder in a presentation copy to Otto Klemperer of the Harper & Row first edition, 1967 Aug (Box 103, Folder 2434)
      - "Transcript of an annotated copy sent to Dr. Otto Klemperer in Zürich to amuse him, July 1967": printed volume (London: Longmans, 1967) with holograph annotations (Box 103, Folder 2435)
      - Advertisements, 1967 (Box 104, Folder 2436)
      - Endorsement by Allen Nevins, typescript carbon (Box 104, Folder 2437)
      - Typed copy of TW notes on "The Eighth Day", 1968
      - Best-seller lists, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2438)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 2439-2457)
        See also: Oversize, Box 163, folders 3914-3915
    - The Eighth Day: Adaptations
      - Play by Dorothy Olney and Jay Dorian (Box 105, Folder 2458-2459)
      - Portion of radio adaptation, 1968 May 25 (Box 105, Folder 2460)
    - The Eighth Day: Related material
      - "An Ethic for Wagon Trains," essay by George Greene, [1970?] (Box 105, Folder 2461)
    - "Geniver Wyatt"
      - Holograph manuscript: Chapters I-IX, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2462)
      - Manuscript notebook: Chapters X-XIV, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2463)
    - Heaven's My Destination
      - Manuscript notebooks, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2464-2466)
      - Holograph manuscript: Chapters 11-13, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2467)
      - Typescript, corrected: Chapters 1-6, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2468)
      - Typescript: Chapters 7-12, n.d. (Box 106, Folder 2469)
      - Author's publicity sheet and advertisements, 1935, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2470)
      - Best-seller list, 1935 (Box 107, Folder 2471)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1934-35, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2472-2476)
    - Heaven's My Destination: Adaptations
      - Screenplay by Ruth Gordon, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2477)
      - BBC Radio adaptation: promotional material, 1944 (Box 107, Folder 2478)
      - Newspaper clipping on projected television version, [1982] (Box 107, Folder 2479)
    - The Ides of March
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2480-2483)
      - Typescript: Books II and III (Box 107, Folder 2484-2485)
      - Typescript: Book IV, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2486)
      - Setting typescript, n.d. (Box 107, Folder 2487)
      - Galley proof, stamped "Author's 1st", 1947 Nov
      - Bound galleys (Box 108, Folder 2488)
      - Holograph manuscript: "Errata list for the London edition, 1948" (Box 108, Folder 2489)
      - Photocopy of Terry Catherman's copy (heavily annotated by Wilder), n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2490)
      - Endorsements: typescript carbon (Box 108, Folder 2491)
      - Advertisements, 1948, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2492)
      - Best-seller lists, 1948 (Box 108, Folder 2493)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1948-61 (Box 108, Folder 2494-2496)
    - The Ides of March: Adaptations
      - Play by Jerome Kilty
        - Typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2497)
        - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2498)
        - Typescript carbon fragment, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2499)
        - "Further suggestions": typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2500)
        - Holograph manuscript fragment of Act II revision, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2501)
        - Bound photocopy, 1962 Jul (Box 108, Folder 2502)
        - Program for London production, 1963 Aug (Box 108, Folder 2503)
        - Newspaper clippings on various productions, 1962-69, n.d. (Box 108, Folder 2504-2506)
        - Reviews, typescript carbon, 1969 (Box 108, Folder 2507)
          With TLS from IW to TW, 1969 Oct 26
    - The Ides of March: Translations
      - German translation by Herlitschka: typescript fragment, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2508)
      - Article from Schweiserische Zeitschrift für Volkswirtschaft und Statistik quoting German translation, 1948 Dec (Box 109, Folder 2509)
        With: letter from Jürg Niehans to Wilder, 1948 Dec 10
      - Italian translation, typescript carbon fragment, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2510)
    - "New York"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2511)
    - Theophilus North
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2512)
      - Holograph manuscript draft outlines and fragments (Box 109, Folder 2513)
      - Bibliography of reference sources, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2514)
      - "Preface," holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2515)
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 109, Folder 2516-2524)
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2525-2532)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2533-2534)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2535)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 110, Folder 2536-2539)
      - Typescript with notes and corrections by Louise Talma, 1973 (Box 111, Folder 2540-2544)
      - Typescript photocopy with corrections by Louise Talma, n.d. (Box 111, Folder 2545-2556)
      - Typescript, "unrevised, complete-- not used as setting copy", n.d. (Box 112, Folder 2557-2560)
      - Galley proof, corrected, n.d.
      - Setting typescript, corrected, 1973 Jun (Box 113, Folder 2561-2564)
      - Proof sheets, 1973 (Box 113, Folder 2565-2567)
      - Bound photocopy of page proofs, 1973 (Box 114, Folder 2568)
      - Holograph manuscript list of corrections to page proofs, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2569)
      - Advertisements, 1973-74, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2570)
      - Best-seller lists, 1973-74 (Box 114, Folder 2571)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1973-74, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2572-2574)
    - Theophilus North: Adaptations
      - Film treatment by James Costigan, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2575)
      - Newspaper clippings about the film Mr. North, 1988 (Box 114, Folder 2576)
    - Thornton Wilder Omnibus
      - Newspaper clippings, 1933-34 (Box 114, Folder 2577)
    - The Woman of Andros
      - Manuscript notebook, 1928-29 (Box 114, Folder 2578)
      - Manuscript notebook, 1929 (Box 114, Folder 2579)
      - Typescript pages, corrected, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2580)
      - Dummy, 1930 (Box 114, Folder 2581)
      - Book jacket, 1930 (Box 114, Folder 2582)
      - Advertisements, 1930 (Box 114, Folder 2583)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1928-30, n.d. (Box 114, Folder 2584-2586)
    - The Woman of Andros: Translations
      - German translation by Herlitschka: printed copy, corrected, with typescript by Herlitschka, 1952 (Box 115, Folder 2587)
      - Articles from German periodicals, 1932, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2588)
    - "Zen"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2589)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - "The American Language"
      - Printed copy, 1952 Jul (Box 115, Folder 2590)
    - "The American Loneliness"
      - Printed copy, 1952 Aug (Box 115, Folder 2591)
      - German translation, typescript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2592)
    - "Aphorisms"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2593)
    - "As We Remember Him"
      - Printed copy, 1943 Mar (Box 115, Folder 2594)
    - "The Care and Feeding of Lies"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2595)
    - "Christian Berard"
      - Typescript, corrected and typescript carbon (Box 115, Folder 2596)
    - "A Diary: First and Last Entry"
      - Holograph manuscript and printed copy in First Person, 1960 Jul (Box 115, Folder 2597)
    - "Don Quixote and Religion"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2598)
    - "Emily Dickinson, the Articulate Inarticulate"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2599)
      - Printed copy, 1952 Nov (Box 115, Folder 2600)
    - "Essay on a Certain Disconnection in Americans"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2601)
    - "Exploration and Explanation"
      - Printed copy in Seventy-Five, 1953 (Box 115, Folder 2602)
    - "A Fable About Flora"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2603)
    - "Five Thousand Letters to Alexander Woollcott"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2604)
      - Printed copy in Harvard Library Bulletin, 1984 (Box 115, Folder 2605)
    - "Giordano Bruno's Last Meal in Finnegans Wake "
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2606)
      - Typescript carbon (second version) (Box 115, Folder 2607)
    - "Goethe und die Weltliteratur"
      - Printed copy, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2608)
    - "Harvard Commencement Address"
      - Press release copy, 1951 Jun (Box 115, Folder 2609)
      - Copy in Harvard Alumni Bulletin, 1951 Jul 7 (Box 115, Folder 2610)
    - "A House in the Country"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2611)
    - "Imaginary Prefaces"
      - Typescript and printed copy (Box 115, Folder 2612)
    - "James Beand Meets the Fl-m-ing I-n"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2613)
    - [James Joyce]
      - Holograph manuscript of article, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2614)
      - "Joyce and the Modern Novel," printed copy (Box 115, Folder 2615)
    - "The Language of Emotion in Shakespeare"
      - Printed copy from The Oberlin Literary Magazine, 1916 Mar (Box 115, Folder 2616)
    - "Lawrenceville School"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 115, Folder 2617)
    - "Leader"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2618)
    - "Das Leben der Amerikaner"
      - Offprints, 1965 Sep (Box 116, Folder 2619)
      - Photocopy of a translation into English, 1979 (Box 116, Folder 2620)
    - "Legends of the Oval"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2621)
    - "The Leviathan"
      - Printed copy, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2622)
    - "The Life of Tom Everage"
      - Manuscript fragment, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2623)
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 116, Folder 2624)
    - "Loose Leaves from a French Diary"
      - Galley proof of S4N, 1920 Jun (Box 116, Folder 2625)
    - Lope de Vega
      - Notes, holograph and typescript (Box 116, Folder 2626-2632)
      - Notes, holograph and typescript (Box 117, Folder 2633-2640)
      - Printed research material, 1930-65, n.d. (Box 117, Folder 2641a-d)
        Offprints and detached pages of articles concerning the work of Lope de Vega, including several by S. Griswold Morley and Courtney Bruerton
        - "Lope, Pinedo, Some Child Actors and a Lion": holograph manuscript and printed copies from Romance Philology, 1953, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2641-2643)
        - "New Aids Toward Dating the Early Plays of Lope de Vega": holograph manuscript, typescript carbon, and offprints (Box 118, Folder 2644-2646)
        - "Thornton Wilder on Lope de Vega": typescript and playbill, 1957, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2647-2648)
    - "Lucas School"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2649)
    - "Madrigals"
      - Holograph manuscript, [1915?] (Box 118, Folder 2650)
    - "The Marriage of Zabett"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2651)
      - Printed copy in Oberlin Literary Magazine, 1917 Jun (Box 118, Folder 2652)
    - "Memorandum" (concerning Latin American trip)
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript carbon, 1941 (Box 118, Folder 2653)
    - "The Miracles and Death of Doma y Venuzias"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2654)
    - "Mouthfulls"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2655)
    - "The Myth and the Novel"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2656)
    - The Norton Lectures
      - I. "Towards an American Language"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2657-2658)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2659-2660)
        - Revision: manuscript, typescript and printed copy, 1964, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2661)
      - II. "Thoreau"
        - Holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 118, Folder 2662-2664)
        - Manuscript and typescript, corrected (Box 118, Folder 2665)
        - Manuscript fragments, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2666-2670)
        - Typescript fragments, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2671)
        - Galley proof, 1952 May 14
      - III. "Emily Dickinson"
        - Holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2672-2673)
      - IV. "Whitman"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2674)
      - V. "Poe"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2675)
      - VI. "Melville"
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2676)
      - Unidentified manuscript fragments, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2677-2680)
    - "The Old Days"
      - Printed copy and photocopy in Thacher School Semicentennial Publications (Box 119, Folder 2681)
    - "On Reading the Great Letter-Writers"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2682)
    - "Our Unknown Phrasemaker"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2683)
    - P.E.N. Latin America talks
      - Holograph manuscripts, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2684-2686)
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2687)
    - Peace Prize Address
      - Typescript, 1967 Oct 6 (Box 119, Folder 2688)
    - "The Planetary Mind"
      - Printed copy, 1950 (Box 119, Folder 2689)
    - "A Platform and a Passion Or Two"
      - Galley proof, 1957
      - Printed copy in Harper's Bazaar, 1957 Oct (Box 119, Folder 2690)
    - "Playgoing Nights"
      - Printed copy in Theatre Arts Monthly, 1929 Jun (Box 119, Folder 2691)
    - "A Playwright's View of Brattle"
      - Printed copy in The Prompter, 1951 May (Box 119, Folder 2692)
    - Poems
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript (Box 119, Folder 2693)
    - "Précautions inutiles"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2694)
    - "Preface to Three Plays "
      - Typescript carbon, 1957 Jul (Box 119, Folder 2694a)
        With: translation into German by Herberth Herlitschka, typescript carbons
    - "A Sapphic Ode"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2695)
    - "Sentences"
      - Printed copy in The Double Dealer, 1922 Sep (Box 119, Folder 2696)
    - "The Shelley Centenary"
      - Printed copy, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2697)
    - "The Silent Generation"
      - Printed copy in Harper's, 1953 Apr (Box 119, Folder 2698)
      - Printed copy: textbook excerpt, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2699)
    - "Sofa Stuffed with Emeralds"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2700)
    - "Some Passages from Joyce's Finnegans Wake "
      - Typescript mimeograph of passages for a lecture at the Romance Language Club, 1959 Apr 23 (Box 119, Folder 2701)
    - "Some Thoughts on Playwriting"
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2702)
      - Typescript carbon of German translation, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2703)
    - "Stein Makes Sense"
      - Printed copy in '47, 1947 (Box 119, Folder 2704)
    - "The Story of Caeone and Acuthina"
      - Typescript, n.d. (Box 119, Folder 2705)
    - "The Three Plannings"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2706)
    - [Tribute to John Marin]
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2707)
    - "Tribute to Dean Woodbridge"
      - Holograph manuscript and typescript, incomplete (Box 120, Folder 2708)
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2709)
    - "We Are the Planets"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2710)
    - "The Willow of Monterey"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2711)
    - "World Literature and the Modern Mind"
      - Galleys, 1950 (Box 120, Folder 2712)
    - "XJB Broadcasting Station"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2713)
  - CONTRIBUTIONS TO WORKS BY OTHERS
    - Beer-Hofmann, Richard: Jacob's Dream
      - Preface
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2714)
        - Typescript carbon of German translation, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2715)
        - Galley proof of German translation, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2716)
        - Annotated photocopy, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2717)
    - Catalogue of the Exhibition of Swiss Books
      - Introduction
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2718)
        - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2719)
    - Plutarch: Antony
      - Introduction
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2720)
    - Schiffeler, ----: Inns
      - Introduction
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2721)
        - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2722)
    - Sophocles: Oedipus the King
      - Introduction
        - Typescripts, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2723-2724)
    - Stein, Gertrude: Four in America
      - Introduction
        - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2725)
        - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2726)
        - Galley proof, corrected by Wilder, annotated by Donald Gallup, 1947 Jul
  - REVIEWS OF WORKS BY OTHERS
    - "Review of The Challenge "
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2727)
    - "Review of The Girl in the Limousine "
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2728)
    - [Review of] "The Letters of Henry James"
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2729)
    - "Review of 'Quick Work'"
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2730)
    - "Review of Too Many Husbands "
      - Typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2731)
  - UNTITLED INCOMPLETE WRITINGS
    - Untitled opera
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2732-2733)
    - Untitled poems
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2734)
    - Untitled fragments
      - Holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 120, Folder 2735-2740)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS: ON THORNTON WILDER
    - Adler, Henry
      - "Thornton Wilder's Theater," photocopy, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2741)
    - Andrews, Clark
      - "To Us He Was Always T.W.," printed article from Yankee, 1978 Sep (Box 121, Folder 2742)
        With: note by Isabel Wilder concerning the success of her novel Mother of Four
    - Baker, John L.
      - "Thornton Wilder: The Grand Old Man at 76," printed, in Publisher's Weekly, 1973 Sep 17 (Box 121, Folder 2743)
    - Behrman, S. N.
      - "Thornton Wilder, America's Universal Man," proof sheets and printed copy, 1974 Feb, May (Box 121, Folder 2744)
        Proof sheets annotated by Wilder
    - Bryer, Jackson R.
      - "Thornton Wilder and the Reviewers," offprint, 1964 (Box 121, Folder 2745)
    - Coe, Richard
      - Untitled speech on Thornton Wilder given at "great lakes shakespeare festival," typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2746)
    - Daniels, Mabel
      - "Thornton Wilder--A Musical Memoir," printed article from Radcliffe Quarterly, 1969 May (Box 121, Folder 2747)
    - Evarts, John
      - "Pages from a Journal: March, 1934," typescript carbon, signed, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2748)
    - four quarters: Thornton Wilder number
      - Articles include Richard H. Goldstone, "The Wilder Image"; Donald Haberman, "The Americanization of Thornton Wilder"; Isabel Wilder, "Embroidery, An Idyll", 1967 May (Box 121, Folder 2749)
    - Frenz, Horst
      - "The Reception of Thornton Wilder's Plays in Germany," offprint from Modern Drama, 1960 Sep (Box 121, Folder 2750)
    - Gassner, John
      - "The Two Worlds of Thornton Wilder," typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2751)
    - Gibbs, Wolcott
      - "Finnegan's Teeth," printed, from New Yorker, [1942] (Box 121, Folder 2752)
        Annotated by Isabel Wilder and William Lyon Phelps
    - Glenn, C. Leslie
      - "I Remember Thornton Wilder," printed, n.d. (Box 121, Folder 2753)
    - Grebanier, Bernard
      - "Thornton Wilder," typescript photocopy, corrected and annotated (Box 121, Folder 2754)
    - Isaacs, Edith J. R.
      - "Thornton Wilder in Person," printed, in Theatre Arts, 1943 Jan (Box 121, Folder 2755)
    - Kepes, Anna
      - "Thornton Wilder," printed, in Vigilia, 1938 Nov (Box 121, Folder 2755a)
    - Kosok, Heinz
      - "Thornton Wilder: Ein Literaturbericht," offprint, annotated by Wilder, 1964 (Box 121, Folder 2756)
    - Lerch, Emil
      - "Thornton Wilders jüngster Roman Theophilus North inscribed to Wilder, 1975 (Box 121, Folder 2757)
    - Lloyd, Allen Dennis
      - "The Shudder of Awe: a Study of the Novels of Thornton Wilder," typescript, 1968 May (Box 121, Folder 2758-2764)
    - Mambrino, Jean
      - "Thornton Wilder: From the Transitory to the Eternal," typescript photocopy, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2765)
        "Lecture given at St. Paul's University (Minneapolis) during the Drama Workshop, Aug. 18-27, 1966"
    - Marston, Donald
      - "The Theater of Thornton Wilder," in Chrysalis, 1954 (Box 122, Folder 2766)
    - Mauranges, Jean-Paul
      - "Der Einfluss Thornton Wilders auf das literarishe Schaffen von Friedrich Dürrenmatt und Max Frisch," offprint, inscribed to Wilder, [1974?] (Box 122, Folder 2766a)
    - Phelps, William Lyon
      - "Preface," typescript corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2767)
        Introduction to an edition of The Bridge of San Luis Rey ?
    - Pini, Richard
      - "The Humanism of Thornton Wilder," typescript and typescript carbon, incomplete (Box 122, Folder 2768-2770)
    - Pixberg, Hermann
      - "Thornton Niven Wilder: Der letzte Puritaner der Weltliteratur," printed, 1962 (Box 122, Folder 2771)
    - Popper, Hermine L.
      - "The Universe of Thornton Wilder," printed article from Harper's, 1965 Jun (Box 122, Folder 2772-2773)
    - Rogers, Vivian
      - Untitled article concerning Thornton Wilder and his South American experience, typescript carbon, [1941] (Box 122, Folder 2774)
        With: TLS from Vivian Rogers to Mrs. A. P. Wilder, 1941 Feb 27
    - Schlueter, Paul
      - "Literature and Religion: Thornton Wilder's The Eighth Day, typescript photocopy, 1970 (Box 122, Folder 2775)
    - Souvaine, Diane Loring
      - "Thornton Wilder: An Affirmation of Man," typescript carbon, 1975 Mar 17 (Box 122, Folder 2776)
    - Stressau, Hermann
      - "Thornton Wilder": review offprint, 1974 (Box 122, Folder 2777)
    - Time
      - "An Obliging Man," printed, 1953 Jan 12 (Box 122, Folder 2778)
    - Ulrich, Dorothy Livingston
      - "Thornton Wilder, A Classic of Tomorrow," printed, in Avocations, 1937 Dec (Box 122, Folder 2779)
    - Vega, Gloria Salvo
      - "Thornton Wilder: His Originality as a Dramatist," printed, 1972 (Box 122, Folder 2780)
        Thesis submitted to the Universidad Católica de Chile
    - Viswanatham, K.
      - "The Bridge that Wilder Built," offprint, inscribed, 1969 (Box 122, Folder 2781)
    - Woolcott, Alexander
      - "Mr. Wilder Urges Us On," typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2782)
  - WRITINGS OF OTHERS: NOT WILDER-RELATED
    - Abril, Xavier
      - Preface to Antologia de César Vallejo, printed, inscribed to Wilder and annotated by him, 1942 Sep (Box 122, Folder 2783)
    - Arjona, J. H.
      - "Did Lope de Vega Write the Extant El Príncipe Melancholico inscribed to Wilder, 1956 (Box 122, Folder 2784)
    - Barish, Jonas A.
      - Offprints: "Yvor Winters and the Antimimetic Prejudice;" "Exhibitionism and the Anti-Theatrical Prejudice;" "Antitheatrical Prejudice in the Nineteenth Century", 1969-71 (Box 122, Folder 2785)
        All inscribed to Wilder
    - Behrmann, S. N.
      - "People in a Diary--I," printed, 1972 May 13 (Box 122, Folder 2786)
    - Bénet, Stephen Vincent [?]
      - "Passing Out," typescript, signed "Stephen Vincent Bénet", n.d. (Box 122, Folder 2787)